# Michał Wadowski

# Senior Java Developer

# Contact

**Address** 

Warsaw, Poland

Phone

+48 796 334 459

E-mail

wadosm@gmail.com

Github

github.com/Michal-Wadowski

Linkedin

linkedin.com/in/michal-wadowski

## **Experience and knowledge**

#### Programming languages / technologies

Java: JUnit/Mockito, Lombok, Hibernate Spring: Boot, Security, JPA, Cloud, Kafka Javasript: ES6, JSX, ReactJS, Redux

Python: DataFrame, Numpy

**Databases** 

PostgreSQL/pgSQL, MongoDB,

Liquibase

Other tools / technologies

Kubernetes, Docker compose, AWS,

Azure, Maven, GIT, Jenkins

Good practices

TDD, DDD, Clean Architecture, software

design patterns

IntelliJ IDEA

IDE

Operating systems

Linux, Windows

Software Development Model

**SCRUM** 

Languages and technologies in past

Android in Kotlin

C, C++

I'm a software development passionate with over 14 years of experience in various technologies and languages. I have been working in Java oriented projects for 5 years mostly using Spring Boot / Security / JPA in combination with PostgreSQL & MongoDB, Kafka, Docker Compose, Kubernetes on AWS & Azure infrastructure. I have frontend background especially in ReactJS and Redux. I value TDD, Clean Code and other good programming practices.

# **Professional experience**

**HSBC Service Delivery** (Polska) Sp. z o.o.

via Mindbox S.A.

08.2022 - 12.2024

Senior Java Developer

Developing "Strategic Financial Planning" internal business application written in Java 8 - 21 with **Spring Boot** in microservices architecture.

Technologies used: JUnit & Mockito, Java Reactor, Lombok, PostgreSQL & Oracle + Liquibase

Kubernetes with AWS, Jenkins and ReactJS were

used in project as well

Orange Polska S.A.

02.2022 - 07.2022

Java Developer

Developing microservices for streaming platform using Kafka, MongoDB and Java Reactor

Orange Polska S.A.

02.2021 - 07.2022

**Java Developer** 

https://www.eclipse.org/leshan in Java for IoT communication protocol (Lightweight M2M).

Developing Eclipse Leshan library

Orange Polska S.A.

**Java Developer** 

08.2020 - 07.2022

Developing research application ThingIn The City using Spring Boot and PostgreSQL technologies.

Orange Polska S.A.

**Android Developer** 

03.2020 - 01.2021

Developing mobile application for technicians

using Live Objects platform

https://liveobjects.orange-business.com with Android Studio in Java and Kotlin languages.

As a development model was used SCRUM

framework.

Awans Sp. z o. o.

06.2014 - 02.2020

**Full-stack Developer** 

Developing https://awanser.pl business platform

using technologies:

Frontend: ReactJS with Redux and Ecmascript 6,

CSS. LESS and SCSS

Backend: PHP and CakePHP framework, PostgreSQL database system, Azure

#### Courses

Creating  $\mu$ Services using Spring Cloud and Docker

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Spring Framework II

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Pragmatic refactoring using DDD techniques

https://bottega.com.pl

Clean Code in Java

https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

Test-Driven Development in practice https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

# **Useful characteristics**

- Writing good quality code
- Experienced in working with legacy systems
- IT technologies quick learner
- Teamwork skills
- Independence and responsibility

## Languages

Polish

Native

**English** 

B2

## **Passions & hobbies**

- Programming microcontrollers and developing electronic circuits
- Building and training artificial neural networks
- Developing applications and devices for own needs
- Astronomy, quantum physics and science in general

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o. 01.2013 - 05.2014	Java Developer  Developing integration layer with ePUAP system in  Java and PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL
Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o. 10.2011 - 12.2012	Software Developer  Developing of business application in Delphi and PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL
iDelfi Polska Sp. z o. o. 11.2009 - 12.2010	Full-stack Developer  Developing internet application for HACCP management in technologies: Ruby on Rails, Javascript, jQuery, MySQL

# **Training**

March 2022	<u>I (PSD I)</u>
Education	
2009 - 2011	University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn
	Field of study: Computer science
	M. Sc.
	Hart and the state of the state

Duefessional Commo Developer

2005 - 2008

University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn
Field of study: Computer systems
Undergraduate course